<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literaturereview on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/literaturereview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literaturereview on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 17:05:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/literaturereview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coarse PM and measurement error paper</title>
      <link>/2011/11/08/coarse-pm-and-measurement-error-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 17:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/11/08/coarse-pm-and-measurement-error-paper/</guid>
      <description>Howard Chang, a former PhD student of mine now at Emory, just published a paper on a measurement error model for estimating the health effects of coarse particulate matter (PM). This is a cool paper that deals with the problem that coarse PM tends to be very spatially heterogeneous. Coarse PM is a bit of a hot topic now because there is currently no national ambient air quality standard for coarse PM specifically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archetypal Athletes</title>
      <link>/2011/10/24/archetypal-athletes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 13:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/10/24/archetypal-athletes/</guid>
      <description>Here is a cool paper on the ArXiv about archetypal athletes. The basic idea is to look at a large number of variables for each player and identify multivariate outliers or extremes. These outliers are the archetypes talked about in the title. According to his analysis the author claims the best players (for different reasons, i.e. different archetypes) in the NBA in 2009&amp;frasl;2010 were: Taj Gibson, Anthony Morrow, and Kevin Durant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When overconfidence is good</title>
      <link>/2011/09/15/when-overconfidence-is-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/15/when-overconfidence-is-good/</guid>
      <description>A paper came out in the latest issue of Nature called the &amp;#8220;Evolution of Confidence&amp;#8221;. The authors describe a simple model where two participants are competing for a resource. They can either both claim the resource, only one can claim the resource, or neither can. If the ratio of the value of the resource over the cost of competition is good enough, then it makes sense to be overconfident about your abilities to obtain it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>