<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>D3.js on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/d3.js/</link>
    <description>Recent content in D3.js on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 10:26:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/d3.js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (1/27/2013)</title>
      <link>/2013/01/27/sunday-datastatistics-link-roundup-1272013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 10:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/27/sunday-datastatistics-link-roundup-1272013/</guid>
      <description>Wisconsin is decoupling the education and degree granting components of education. This means if you take a MOOC like mine, Brian&amp;rsquo;s or Roger&amp;rsquo;s and there is an equivalent class to pass at Wisconsin, you can take the exam and get credit. This is big. (via Rafa) 1. Wisconsin is decoupling the education and degree granting components of education. This means if you take a MOOC like mine, Brian&amp;rsquo;s or Roger&amp;rsquo;s and there is an equivalent class to pass at Wisconsin, you can take the exam and get credit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (2/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/02/12/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-2-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 14:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/12/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-2-12/</guid>
      <description>An awesome alternative to D3.js - R&amp;#8217;s svgAnnotation package. Here&amp;#8217;s the paper in JSS. I feel like this is one step away from gaining broad use in the statistics community - it still feels a little complicated building the graphics, but there is plenty of flexibility there. I feel like a great project for a student at any level would be writing some easy wrapper functions for these functions.  How to run R on your Android device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (2/5)</title>
      <link>/2012/02/06/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-2-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/06/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-2-5/</guid>
      <description>Cool app, you can write out an equation on the screen and it translates the equation to latex. Via Andrew G. Yet another D3 tutorial. Stay tuned for some cool stuff on this front here at Simply Stats in the near future. Via Vishal. Our favorite Greek statistician in the news again.  How measurement of academic output harms science. Related: is submitting scientific papers too time consuming? Stay tuned for more on this topic this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup</title>
      <link>/2012/01/15/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 15:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/15/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup/</guid>
      <description>Statistics help for journalists (don&amp;#8217;t forget to keep rating stories!) This is the kind of thing that could grow into a statisteracy page. The author also has a really nice plug for public schools.  An interactive graphic to determine if you are in the 1% from the New York Times (I&amp;#8217;m not&amp;#8230;). Mike Bostock&amp;#8217;s d3.js presentation, this is some really impressive visualization software. You have to change the slide numbers manually but it is totally worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>