<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 12:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you own or rent?</title>
      <link>/2012/01/10/do-you-own-or-rent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 12:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/10/do-you-own-or-rent/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to computing, history has gone back and forth between what I would call the &amp;#8220;owner model&amp;#8221; and the &amp;#8220;renter model&amp;#8221;. The question is what&amp;#8217;s the best approach and how do you determine that?
Back in the day when people like John von Neumann were busy inventing the computer to work out H-bomb calculations, there was more or less a renter model in place. Computers were obviously quite expensive and so not everyone could have one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A statistician and Apple fanboy buys a Chromebook...and loves it!</title>
      <link>/2012/01/09/a-statistician-and-apple-fanboy-buys-a-chromebook-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/09/a-statistician-and-apple-fanboy-buys-a-chromebook-and/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;#8217;t mean to brag, but I was an early Apple Fanboy - not sure that is something to brag about now that I write it down. I convinced my advisor to go to all Macs in our lab in 2004. Since then I have been pretty dedicated to the brand, dutifully shelling out almost 2g&amp;#8217;s every time I need a new laptop. I love the way Macs just work (until they don&amp;#8217;t and you need a new laptop).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple this is ridiculous - you gotta upgrade to upgrade!?</title>
      <link>/2011/11/27/apple-this-is-ridiculous-you-gotta-upgrade-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 19:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/11/27/apple-this-is-ridiculous-you-gotta-upgrade-to/</guid>
      <description>So along with a few folks here around Hopkins we have been kicking around the idea of developing an app for the iPhone/Android. I&amp;#8217;ll leave the details out for now (other than to say stay tuned!).
But to start developing an app for the iPhone, you need a version of Xcode, Apple&amp;#8217;s development environment. The latest version of Xcode is version 4, which can only be installed with the latest version of Mac OS X Lion (10.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>