<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Policy on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Policy on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 11:25:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Statisticians and computer scientists - if there is no code, there is no paper</title>
      <link>/2013/01/23/statisticians-and-computer-scientists-if-there-is-no-code-there-is-no-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 11:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/23/statisticians-and-computer-scientists-if-there-is-no-code-there-is-no-paper/</guid>
      <description>I think it has been beat to death that the incentives in academia lean heavily toward producing papers and less toward producing/maintaining software. There are people that are way, way more knowledgeable than me about building and maintaining software. For example, Titus Brown hit a lot of the key issues in his interview. The open source community is also filled with advocates and researchers who know way more about this than I do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozone rules</title>
      <link>/2011/11/20/ozone-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 18:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/11/20/ozone-rules/</guid>
      <description>A recent article in the New York Times describes the backstory behind the decision to not revise the ozone national ambient air quality standard. This article highlights the reality of balancing the need to set air pollution regulation to protect public health and the desire to get re-elected. Not having ever served in politics (does being elected to the faculty senate count?) I can&amp;#8217;t comment on the political aspect. But I wanted to highlight some of the scientific evidence that goes into developing these standards.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>