<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mooc on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/mooc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mooc on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 09:01:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mooc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking about MOOCs on MPT Direct Connection</title>
      <link>/2013/05/06/talking-about-moocs-on-mpt-direct-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 09:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/06/talking-about-moocs-on-mpt-direct-connection/</guid>
      <description>Watch Monday, April 29, 2013 on PBS. See more from Direct Connection. I appeared on Maryland Public Television&amp;rsquo;s Direct Connection with Jeff Salkin last Monday to talk about MOOCs (along with our Dean Mike Klag).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast #6: Data Analysis MOOC Post-mortem</title>
      <link>/2013/03/25/podcast-6-data-analysis-mooc-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 13:34:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/25/podcast-6-data-analysis-mooc-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>Jeff and I talk about Jeff&amp;rsquo;s recently completed MOOC on Data Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By introducing competition open online education will improve teaching at top universities</title>
      <link>/2013/01/08/by-introducing-competition-open-online-education-will-improve-teaching-at-top-universities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 10:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/08/by-introducing-competition-open-online-education-will-improve-teaching-at-top-universities/</guid>
      <description>It is no secret that faculty evaluations at top universities weigh research much more than teaching. This is not surprising given that, among other reasons, global visibility comes from academic innovation (think Nobel Prizes) not classroom instruction. Come promotion time the peer review system carefully examines your publication record and ability to raise research funds. External experts within your research area are asked if you are a leader in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing for Data Analysis Returns</title>
      <link>/2012/12/14/computing-for-data-analysis-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 09:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/14/computing-for-data-analysis-returns/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that my course Computing for Data Analysis will return to Coursera on January 2nd, 2013. While I had previously announced that the course would be presented again right here, it made more sense to do it again on Coursera where it is (still) free and the platform there is much richer. For those of you who missed it the last time around, this is your chance to take it and learn a little R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast #5: Coursera Debrief</title>
      <link>/2012/11/19/podcast-5-coursera-debrief-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/19/podcast-5-coursera-debrief-2/</guid>
      <description>Jeff and I talk with Brian Caffo about teaching MOOCs on Coursera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing for Data Analysis (Simply Statistics Edition)</title>
      <link>/2012/10/29/computing-for-data-analysis-simply-statistics-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/29/computing-for-data-analysis-simply-statistics-edition/</guid>
      <description>As the entire East Coast gets soaked by Hurricane Sandy, I can&amp;#8217;t help but think that this is the perfect time to&amp;#8230;take a course online! Well, as long as you have electricity, that is. I live in a heavily tree-lined area and so it&amp;#8217;s only a matter of time before the lights cut out on me (I&amp;#8217;d better type quickly!). I just finished teaching my course Computing for Data Analysis through Coursera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (9/23/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/09/23/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-9-23-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 13:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/23/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-9-23-12/</guid>
      <description>Harvard Business school is getting in on the fun, calling the data scientist the sexy profession for the 21st century. Although I am a little worried that by the time it gets into a Harvard Business document, the hype may be outstripping the real promise of the discipline. Still, good news for statisticians! (via Rafa via Francesca D.&amp;#8217;s Facebook feed).  The counterpoint is this article which suggests that data scientists might be able to be replaced by tools/software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (8/12/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/08/12/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-8-12-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 19:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/12/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-8-12-12/</guid>
      <description>An interesting blog post about the top N reasons to do a Ph.D. in bioinformatics or computational biology. A couple of things that I find interesting and could actually be said of any program in biostatistics as well are: computing is the key skill of the 21st century and computational skills are highly transferrable. Via Andrew J.  Here is an interesting auto-complete map of the United States where the prompt was, &amp;#8220;Why is [state] so&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we are teaching massive open online courses (MOOCs) in R/statistics for Coursera</title>
      <link>/2012/08/10/why-we-are-teaching-massive-open-online-courses-moocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 14:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/10/why-we-are-teaching-massive-open-online-courses-moocs/</guid>
      <description>Editor&amp;#8217;s Note: This post written by Roger Peng and Jeff Leek.  A couple of weeks ago, we announced that we would be teaching free courses in Computing for Data Analysis and Data Analysis on the Coursera platform. At the same time, a number of other universities also announced partnerships with Coursera leading to a large number of new offerings. That, coupled with a new round of funding for Coursera, led to press coverage in the New York Times, the Atlantic, and other media outlets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>