<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 19:59:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (8/12/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/08/12/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-8-12-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 19:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/12/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-8-12-12/</guid>
      <description>An interesting blog post about the top N reasons to do a Ph.D. in bioinformatics or computational biology. A couple of things that I find interesting and could actually be said of any program in biostatistics as well are: computing is the key skill of the 21st century and computational skills are highly transferrable. Via Andrew J.  Here is an interesting auto-complete map of the United States where the prompt was, &amp;#8220;Why is [state] so&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An R script for estimating future inflation via the Treasury market</title>
      <link>/2012/02/06/an-r-script-for-estimating-future-inflation-via-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 13:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/06/an-r-script-for-estimating-future-inflation-via-the/</guid>
      <description>One factor that is critical for any financial planning is estimating what future inflation will be. For example, if you&amp;#8217;re saving money in an instrument that gains 3% per year, and inflation is estimated to be 4% per year, well then you&amp;#8217;re losing money in real terms.
There are a variety of ways to estimate the rate of future inflation. You could, for example, use past rates as an estimate of future rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selling the Power of Statistics</title>
      <link>/2011/11/30/selling-the-power-of-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 14:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/11/30/selling-the-power-of-statistics/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago we learned that Warren Buffett is a big IBM fan (a $10 billion fan, that is). Having heard that I went over to the IBM web site to see what they&amp;#8217;re doing these days. For starters, they&amp;#8217;re not selling computers anymore! At least not the kind that I would use. One of the big things they do now is &amp;#8220;Business Analytics and Optimization&amp;#8221; (i.e. statistics), which is one of the reasons they bought SPSS and then later Algorithmics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>