<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pro Tips on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/pro-tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pro Tips on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 14:00:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/pro-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pro-tips for graduate students (Part 3)</title>
      <link>/2012/09/26/pro-tips-for-graduate-students-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/26/pro-tips-for-graduate-students-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This is part of the ongoing series of pro tips for graduate students, check out parts one and two for the original installments.  Learn how to write papers in a very clear and simple style. Whenever you can write in plain English, skip jargon as much as possible, and make the approach you are using understandable and clear. This can (sometimes) make it harder to get your papers into journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pro Tips for Grad Students in Statistics/Biostatistics (Part 2)</title>
      <link>/2012/06/20/pro-tips-for-grad-students-in-statistics-biostatistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 15:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/06/20/pro-tips-for-grad-students-in-statistics-biostatistics/</guid>
      <description>This is the second in my series on pro tips for graduate students in statistics/biostatistics. For more tips, see part 1.  Meet with seminar speakers. When you go on the job market face recognition is priceless. I met Scott Zeger at UW when I was a student. When I came for an interview I already knew him (and Ingo, and Rafa, and &amp;#8230;.). An even better idea&amp;#8230;ask a question during the seminar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pro Tips for Grad Students in Statistics/Biostatistics (Part 1)</title>
      <link>/2012/06/18/pro-tips-for-grad-students-in-statistics-biostatistics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 16:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/06/18/pro-tips-for-grad-students-in-statistics-biostatistics-2/</guid>
      <description>I just finished teaching a Ph.D. level applied statistical methods course here at Hopkins. As part of the course, I gave one &amp;#8220;pro-tip&amp;#8221; a day; something I wish I had learned in graduate school that has helped me in becoming a practicing applied statistician. Here are the first three, more to come soon.   A major component of being a researcher is knowing what&amp;#8217;s going on in the research community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>