<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Ideas on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/project-ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project Ideas on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 15:12:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/project-ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A statistician loves the #insurancepoll...now how do we analyze it?</title>
      <link>/2012/10/15/a-statistician-loves-the-insurancepoll-now-how-do-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 15:12:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/15/a-statistician-loves-the-insurancepoll-now-how-do-we/</guid>
      <description>Amanda Palmer broke Twitter yesterday with her insurance poll. She started off just talking about how hard it is for musicians who rarely have health insurance, but then wandered into polling territory. She sent out a request for people to respond with the following information:
 quick twitter poll. 1) COUNTRY?! 2) profession? 3) insured? 4) if not, why not, if so, at what cost per month (or covered by job)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics project ideas for students (part 2)</title>
      <link>/2012/10/04/statistics-project-ideas-for-students-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 17:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/04/statistics-project-ideas-for-students-part-2/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago I wrote a post on statistics projects ideas for students. In honor of the first Simply Statistics Coursera offering, Computing for Data Analysis, here is a new list of student projects for folks excited about trying out those new R programming skills. Again we have rated each project with my best guess difficulty and effort required. Happy computing!
Data Analysis
 Use city data to predict areas with the highest risk for parking tickets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Killer App for Peer Review</title>
      <link>/2011/09/22/the-killer-app-for-peer-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/22/the-killer-app-for-peer-review/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago, over at Genomes Unzipped, Joe Pickrell asked, &amp;#8220;Why publish science in peer reviewed journals?&amp;#8221; He points out the flaws with the current peer review system and suggests how we can do better. What he suggests is missing is the killer app for peer review. Well, PLoS has now developed an API, where you can easily access tons of data on the papers published in those journals including downloads, citations, number of social bookmarks, and mentions in major science blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>