<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Landhood</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Landhood</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Click here to download my CV Click here to download my Scientific Statement  PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE
 Since 2019 • Lecturer in Rural Geography • CIHEAM-IAMM (France) 2017 - 2019 • Postdoctoral Research Fellow in Economic Geography • University of Southampton (UK) 2016 - 2018 • Teaching Fellow in Applied Social Sciences • University of Winchester (UK) 2014 - 2018 • Research Assistant in Geography • DECCMA (UK) 2017 (5 months) • Knowledge Transfer Officer • IRD (France &amp;amp; Morocco) 2014 - 2017 • Teaching Assistant in Geography • University of Southampton (UK) 2013 - 2014 • Research Associate in Agricultural Economics • GRET (Tanzania &amp;amp; Uganda) 2012 (6 months) • Appraisal, Monitoring and Evaluation Manager • ACTED (Chad) 2011 - 2012 • Research Associate in Rural Development • CIRAD (Vietnam)   QUALIFICATIONS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>CURRENT PROJECTS
 2019 - 2023 • Sustainable Hub to Engage into Rural Policies with Actors (SHERPA) Gather relevant knowledge and opinions that contribute to the formulation of recommendations for future policies relevant to EU rural areas. It will create a science-society-policy interface which provides a hub for knowledge and policy. In this project, I am the scientific coordinator of WP3: Screening of rural trends and rural policies. Funded by the European Union (EU) under the Horizon 2020 Research and Innovation Programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/</guid>
      <description>2020 T. Berchoux, G.R. Watmough, F. Amoako Johnson, C.W. Hutton, P.M. Atkinson. 2020. Collective influence of household and community capitals on agricultural employment as a measure of rural poverty in the Mahanadi Delta, India. Ambio. DOI: 10.1007/s13280-019-01150-9
 2019 T. Berchoux, G.R. Watmough, C.W. Hutton, P.M. Atkinson. 2019. Agricultural shocks and drivers of livelihood precariousness across Indian rural communities. Landscape and Urban Planning. DOI: 10.​1016/​j.​landurbplan.​2019.​04.​014
T. Berchoux, C.W. Hutton. 2019. Spatial associations between household and community livelihood capitals in rural territories: An example from the Mahanadi Delta, India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>My work uses a combination of empirical spatial approach with participatory research and quantitative economic modelling to advance knowledge on sustainable and inclusive development of rural territories. Click here to get to a list of publications.
My ongoing research into the economic analysis of rural territories examines how rural finance, agricultural marketing, access to resources, and land use patterns shape regional economic development and rural livelihood opportunities, especially in the context of climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Agricultural and food policies (French)   Sustainable development in the Mediterranean (French)   GIS for territorial diagnosis (French) Module taught at the Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Montpellier (CIHEAM-IAMM) to the Masters programs I3P and GAT on how to use GIS for territorial diagnosis. It introduces a systematic methodology for the analysis of specific spatial units, such as functional urban areas, aimed at identifying key challenges and opportunities as a basis for strategic investment decisions for a certain area, city or region, in line with a place-based and integrated approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Producing an outreach video</title>
      <link>/2017/10/02/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/02/video/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, following the showcase of a video summarising my research at the yearly DECCMA Consortium Meeting, I was commissioned to design and produce an outreach video to present the outputs from the Climate Change and Vulnerability Handbook to the Governments and development practitioners of southern African countries. This work was produced following a collaboration between Kulima and CSIR. Please find below a link to the video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conducting fieldwork in a highly stratified society</title>
      <link>/2017/01/03/fieldwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/03/fieldwork/</guid>
      <description>Social issues in rural India Inequalities are omnipresent within Indian rural communities. They are perpetuated by the system of castes, which leads to a social stratification of India’s population. Moreover, vulnerability to external stresses is also driven by gender discrimination, which follows on from the systemic marginalisation of women and the differences of power relationships that exist between men and women, especially in India. In order to get an overview of communities, social scientists have to face the challenge of getting access to the views of such marginalised groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organising the DECCMA Postgraduate Seminar Series</title>
      <link>/2015/05/06/seminars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/06/seminars/</guid>
      <description>As part of DECCMA, a group of postgraduate research students has been established across the project partners. In total, there are about 20 PhD students working within the project, with a substantial and vibrant group of six based at the University of Southampton. Their work complements one another by examining how people are adapting to the physical effects of climate change, covering a broad range of topics from the physical aspects of deltas to their socio-economical dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/forteaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/forteaching/</guid>
      <description>QGIS Tutorial QGIS is a well-developed, open source GIS program, with a wide range of features and great compatability with numerous formats. Furthermore, basic installation includes linkages with other open source GIS tools such as GRASS GIS and SAGA (among others). It is one primary software packages that I use in research and teach in classes.
This tutorial is designed to familiarize GIS users with the general layout, features and tools of QGIS, through working with sample datasets that are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>