<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Landhood</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Landhood</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Producing an outreach video</title>
      <link>/2017/10/02/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/02/video/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, following the showcase of a video summarising my research at the yearly DECCMA Consortium Meeting, I was commissioned to design and produce an outreach video to present the outputs from the Climate Change and Vulnerability Handbook to the Governments and development practitioners of southern African countries. This work was produced following a collaboration between Kulima and CSIR. Please find below a link to the video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conducting fieldwork in a highly stratified society</title>
      <link>/2017/01/03/fieldwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/03/fieldwork/</guid>
      <description>Social issues in rural India Inequalities are omnipresent within Indian rural communities. They are perpetuated by the system of castes, which leads to a social stratification of India’s population. Moreover, vulnerability to external stresses is also driven by gender discrimination, which follows on from the systemic marginalisation of women and the differences of power relationships that exist between men and women, especially in India. In order to get an overview of communities, social scientists have to face the challenge of getting access to the views of such marginalised groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organising the DECCMA Postgraduate Seminar Series</title>
      <link>/2015/05/06/seminars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/06/seminars/</guid>
      <description>As part of DECCMA, a group of postgraduate research students has been established across the project partners. In total, there are about 20 PhD students working within the project, with a substantial and vibrant group of six based at the University of Southampton. Their work complements one another by examining how people are adapting to the physical effects of climate change, covering a broad range of topics from the physical aspects of deltas to their socio-economical dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>