<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salzberg on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/salzberg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Salzberg on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/salzberg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Does NIH fund innovative work?  Does Nature care about publishing accurate articles?</title>
      <link>/2013/01/04/does-nih-fund-innovative-work-does-nature-care-about-publishing-accurate-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/04/does-nih-fund-innovative-work-does-nature-care-about-publishing-accurate-articles/</guid>
      <description>_Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note: In a recent post we disagreed with a Nature article claiming that NIH doesn&amp;rsquo;t support innovation. Our colleague Steven Salzberg actually looked at the data and wrote the guest post below. _
Nature published an article last month with the provocative title &amp;ldquo;Research grants: Conform and be funded.&amp;rdquo; The authors looked at papers with over 1000 citations to find out whether scientists &amp;ldquo;who do the most influential scientific work get funded by the NIH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (11/18/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/11/18/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-11-18-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 14:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/18/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-11-18-12/</guid>
      <description>An interview with Brad Efron about scientific writing. I haven&amp;#8217;t watched the whole interview, but I do know that Efron is one of my favorite writers among statisticians. Slidify, another approach for making HTML5 slides directly from R. I love the idea of making HTML slides, I would definitely do this regularly. But there are a couple of issues I feel still aren&amp;#8217;t resolved: (1) It is still just a little too hard to change the theme/feel of the slides in my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (9/9/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/09/09/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-9-9-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/09/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-9-9-12/</guid>
      <description>Not necessarily statistics related, but pretty appropriate now that the school year is starting. Here is a little introduction to &amp;#8220;how to google&amp;#8221; (via Andrew J.). Being able to &amp;#8220;just google it&amp;#8221; and find answers for oneself without having to resort to asking folks is maybe the #1 most useful skill as a statistician.  A really nice presentation on interactive graphics with the googleVis package. I think one of the most interesting things about the presentation is that it was built with markdown/knitr/slidy (see slide 53).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battling Bad Science</title>
      <link>/2011/09/30/battling-bad-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/30/battling-bad-science/</guid>
      <description>Here is a pretty awesome TED talk by epidemiologist Ben Goldacre where he highlights how science can be used to deceive/mislead. It&amp;#8217;s sort of like epidemiology 101 in 15 minutes. This seems like a highly topical talk. Over on his blog, Steven Salzberg has pointed out that Dr. Oz has recently been engaging in some of these shady practices on his show. Too bad he didn&amp;#8217;t check out the video first.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>