<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 13:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (10/28/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/10/28/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-10-28-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 13:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/28/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-10-28-12/</guid>
      <description>An important article about anti-science sentiment in the U.S. (via David S.). The politicization of scientific issues such as global warming, evolution, and healthcare (think vaccination) makes the U.S. less competitive. I think the lack of statistical literacy and training in the U.S. is one of the sources of the problem. People use/skew/mangle statistical analyses and experiments to support their view and without a statistically well trained public, it all looks &amp;#8220;reasonable and scientific&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (5/27)</title>
      <link>/2012/05/27/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-5-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 17:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/27/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-5-27/</guid>
      <description>Amanda Cox on the process they went through to come up with this graphic about the Facebook IPO. So cool to see how R is used in the development process. A favorite quote of mine, &amp;#8220;But rather than bringing clarity, it just sort of looked chaotic, even to the seasoned chart freaks of 620 8th Avenue.&amp;#8221; One of the more interesting things about posts like this is you get to see how statistics versus a deadline works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Drew Conway - Author of &#34;Machine Learning for Hackers&#34;</title>
      <link>/2012/04/13/interview-with-drew-conway-author-of-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 13:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/04/13/interview-with-drew-conway-author-of-machine/</guid>
      <description>Drew Conway

Drew Conway is a Ph.D. student in Politics at New York University and the co-ordinator of the New York Open Statistical Programming Meetup. He is the creator of the famous (or infamous) data science Venn diagram, the basis for our R function to determine if your a data scientist. He is also the co-author of Machine Learning for Hackers, a book of case studies that illustrates data science from a hacker&amp;#8217;s perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (3/4)</title>
      <link>/2012/03/04/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 14:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/04/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-3-4/</guid>
      <description>A cool article on Github by the folks at Wired. I&amp;#8217;m starting to think the fact that I&amp;#8217;m not on Github is a serious dent in my nerd cred.  Datawrapper - a less intensive, but less flexible open source data visualization creator. I have seen a few of these types of services starting to pop up. I think that some statistics training should be mandatory before people use them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>