<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personalized Medicine on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/personalized-medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personalized Medicine on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 15:53:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/personalized-medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme court vacates ruling on BRCA gene patent!</title>
      <link>/2012/03/26/supreme-court-vacates-ruling-on-brca-gene-patent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 15:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/26/supreme-court-vacates-ruling-on-brca-gene-patent/</guid>
      <description>As Reeves alluded to in his post about the Mayo personalized medicine case, the Supreme Court just vacated the lower court&amp;#8217;s ruling in Association for Molecular Pathology v. Myriad Genetics (No. 11-725). The case has been sent back down to the Federal Circuit for reconsideration in light of the Court&amp;#8217;s decision in Mayo. This means that the Supreme Court thought the two cases were sufficiently similar that the lower courts should take another look using the new direction from Mayo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (3/25)</title>
      <link>/2012/03/25/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-3-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 15:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/25/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-3-25/</guid>
      <description>The psychologist whose experiment didn&amp;#8217;t replicate then went off on the scientists who did the replication experiment is at it again. I don&amp;#8217;t see a clear argument about the facts of the matter in his post, just more name calling. This seems to be a case study in what not to do when your study doesn&amp;#8217;t replicate. More on &amp;#8220;conceptual replication&amp;#8221; in there too.  Berkeley is running a data science course with instructors Jeff Hammerbacher and Mike Franklin, I looked through the notes and it looks pretty amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts from Keith Baggerly on the recently released IOM report on translational omics</title>
      <link>/2012/03/25/some-thoughts-from-keith-baggerly-on-the-recently/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 01:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/25/some-thoughts-from-keith-baggerly-on-the-recently/</guid>
      <description>Shortly after the Duke trial scandal broke, the Institute of Medicine convened a committee to write a report on translational omics. Several statisticians (including one of our interviewees) either served on the committee or provided key testimony. The report came out yesterday. Nature, Nature Medicine, and Science had posts about the release. Keith Baggerly sent an email with his thoughts and he gave me permission to post it here. He starts by pointing out that the Science piece has a key new observation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme court unanimously rules against personalized medicine patent!</title>
      <link>/2012/03/20/supreme-court-unanimously-rules-against-personalized/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 14:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/20/supreme-court-unanimously-rules-against-personalized/</guid>
      <description>Just a few minutes ago the Supreme Court released their decision in the Mayo case, see here for the Simply Statistics summary of the case. The court ruled unanimously that the personalized medicine test could not be patented. Such a strong ruling likely has major implications going forward for the field of personalized medicine. At the end of the day, this decision was based on an interpretation of statistical correlation. Stay tuned for a special in-depth analysis in the next couple of days that will get into the details of the ruling and the implications for personalized medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supreme Court&#39;s interpretation of statistical correlation may determine the future of personalized medicine</title>
      <link>/2011/12/12/the-supreme-courts-interpretation-of-statistical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 23:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/12/the-supreme-courts-interpretation-of-statistical/</guid>
      <description>Summary/Background
The Supreme Court heard oral arguments last week in the case Mayo Collaborative Services vs. Prometheus Laboratories (No 10-1150). At issue is a patent Prometheus Laboratories holds for making decisions about the treatment of disease on the basis of a measurement of a specific, naturally occurring molecule and a corresponding calculation. The specific language at issue is a little technical, but the key claim from the patent under dispute is:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>