<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Careers on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/careers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Careers on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 12:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/careers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finish and publish</title>
      <link>/2011/09/20/finish-and-publish/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/20/finish-and-publish/</guid>
      <description>Roger pointed us to this Amstat news profile of statisticians including one on Francesca Dominici. Francesca has used her statistics skills to become a top environmental scientist. She had this advice for young [academic] statisticians:
 First, I would say find a good mentor in or outside the department. Prioritize, manage your time, and identify the projects you would like to lead. Focus the most productive time of day on those projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistician Profiles</title>
      <link>/2011/09/20/statistician-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/20/statistician-profiles/</guid>
      <description>Just in case you forgot to renew your subscription to Amstat News, there&amp;#8217;s a nice little profile of statisticians (including my good colleague Francesca Dominici) in the latest issue explaining how they ended up where they are.
I remember a few years ago I was at a dinner for our MPH program and the director at the time, Ron Brookmeyer, told all the students to ask the faculty how they ended up in public health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another academic job market option: liberal arts colleges</title>
      <link>/2011/09/15/another-academic-job-market-option-liberal-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/15/another-academic-job-market-option-liberal-arts/</guid>
      <description>Liberal arts colleges are option that falls close to the 75% hard/25% soft option described by Rafa in his advice for folks on the job market. At these schools the teaching load may be even a little heavier than schools like Berkeley/Duke; the students will usually be exclusively undergraduates. Examples of this kind of place are Pomona College, Carleton College, Grinnell College, etc. The teaching load is the focus at places like this, but research plays an increasingly major role for academic faculty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for stats students on the academic job market</title>
      <link>/2011/09/12/advice-for-stats-students-on-the-academic-job-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 13:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/12/advice-for-stats-students-on-the-academic-job-market/</guid>
      <description>Job hunting season is upon us. Openings are already being posted here, here, and here. So you should have your CV, research statement, and web page ready. I highly recommend having a web page. It doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be fancy. Here, here, and here are some good ones ranging from simple to a bit over the top. Minimum requirements are a list of publications and a link to a CV. If you have written software, link to that as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>