<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 11:08:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (1/6/2013)</title>
      <link>/2013/01/06/sunday-datastatistics-link-roundup-162013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 11:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/06/sunday-datastatistics-link-roundup-162013/</guid>
      <description>Not really statistics, but this is an interesting article about how rational optimization by individual actors does not always lead to an optimal solutiohn. Related, ere is the coolest street sign I think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, with a heatmap of traffic density to try to influence commuters. An interesting paper that talks about how clustering is only a really hard problem when there aren&amp;rsquo;t obvious clusters. I was a little disappointed in the paper, because it defines the &amp;ldquo;obviousness&amp;rdquo; of clusters only theoretically by a distance metric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (9/2/2012)</title>
      <link>/2012/09/02/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-9-2-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 13:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/02/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-9-2-2012/</guid>
      <description>Just got back from IBC 2012 in Kobe Japan. I was in an awesome session (organized by the inimitable Lieven Clement) with great talks by Matt McCall, Djork-Arne Clevert, Adetayo Kasim, and Willem Talloen. Willem&amp;#8217;s talk nicely tied in our work and how it plays into the pharmaceutical development process and the bigger theme of big data. On the way home through SFO I saw this hanging in the airport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selling the Power of Statistics</title>
      <link>/2011/11/30/selling-the-power-of-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 14:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/11/30/selling-the-power-of-statistics/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago we learned that Warren Buffett is a big IBM fan (a $10 billion fan, that is). Having heard that I went over to the IBM web site to see what they&amp;#8217;re doing these days. For starters, they&amp;#8217;re not selling computers anymore! At least not the kind that I would use. One of the big things they do now is &amp;#8220;Business Analytics and Optimization&amp;#8221; (i.e. statistics), which is one of the reasons they bought SPSS and then later Algorithmics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>