<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Does NIH fund innovative work?  Does Nature care about publishing accurate articles?</title>
      <link>/2013/01/04/does-nih-fund-innovative-work-does-nature-care-about-publishing-accurate-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/04/does-nih-fund-innovative-work-does-nature-care-about-publishing-accurate-articles/</guid>
      <description>_Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note: In a recent post we disagreed with a Nature article claiming that NIH doesn&amp;rsquo;t support innovation. Our colleague Steven Salzberg actually looked at the data and wrote the guest post below. _
Nature published an article last month with the provocative title &amp;ldquo;Research grants: Conform and be funded.&amp;rdquo; The authors looked at papers with over 1000 citations to find out whether scientists &amp;ldquo;who do the most influential scientific work get funded by the NIH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we are teaching massive open online courses (MOOCs) in R/statistics for Coursera</title>
      <link>/2012/08/10/why-we-are-teaching-massive-open-online-courses-moocs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 14:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/10/why-we-are-teaching-massive-open-online-courses-moocs/</guid>
      <description>Editor&amp;#8217;s Note: This post written by Roger Peng and Jeff Leek.  A couple of weeks ago, we announced that we would be teaching free courses in Computing for Data Analysis and Data Analysis on the Coursera platform. At the same time, a number of other universities also announced partnerships with Coursera leading to a large number of new offerings. That, coupled with a new round of funding for Coursera, led to press coverage in the New York Times, the Atlantic, and other media outlets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>