<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ioannidis on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/ioannidis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ioannidis on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 14:55:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ioannidis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I disagree with Andrew Gelman&#39;s critique of my paper about the rate of false discoveries in the medical literature</title>
      <link>/2013/01/24/why-i-disagree-with-andrew-gelmans-critique-of-my-paper-about-the-rate-of-false-discoveries-in-the-medical-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 14:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/24/why-i-disagree-with-andrew-gelmans-critique-of-my-paper-about-the-rate-of-false-discoveries-in-the-medical-literature/</guid>
      <description>With a colleague, I wrote a paper titled, &amp;ldquo;Empirical estimates suggest most published medical research is true&amp;rdquo; which we quietly posted to ArXiv a few days ago. I posted to the ArXiv in the interest of open science and because we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to delay the dissemination of our approach during the long review process. I didn&amp;rsquo;t email anyone about the paper or talk to anyone about it, except my friends here locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does NIH fund innovative work?  Does Nature care about publishing accurate articles?</title>
      <link>/2013/01/04/does-nih-fund-innovative-work-does-nature-care-about-publishing-accurate-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/04/does-nih-fund-innovative-work-does-nature-care-about-publishing-accurate-articles/</guid>
      <description>_Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note: In a recent post we disagreed with a Nature article claiming that NIH doesn&amp;rsquo;t support innovation. Our colleague Steven Salzberg actually looked at the data and wrote the guest post below. _
Nature published an article last month with the provocative title &amp;ldquo;Research grants: Conform and be funded.&amp;rdquo; The authors looked at papers with over 1000 citations to find out whether scientists &amp;ldquo;who do the most influential scientific work get funded by the NIH.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>