<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jobs on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jobs on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:22:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NIH is looking for an Associate Director for Data Science: Statisticians should consider applying</title>
      <link>/2013/04/08/nih-is-looking-for-an-associate-director-for-data-science-statisticians-should-consider-applying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/04/08/nih-is-looking-for-an-associate-director-for-data-science-statisticians-should-consider-applying/</guid>
      <description>NIH understands the importance of data and several months ago they announced this new position. Here is an excerpt from the add:
 The ADDS will focus on the urgent need and increased opportunities for capitalizing on the expanding collections of biomedical data to advance NIH’s mission. In doing so, the incumbent will provide programmatic NIH-wide leadership for areas of data science that relate to data emanating from many areas of study (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (9/16/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/09/16/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-9-16-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 13:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/16/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-9-16-12/</guid>
      <description>There has been a lot of talk about the Michael Lewis (of Moneyball fame) profile of Obama in Vanity fair. One interesting quote I think deserves a lot more discussion is: &amp;#8220;On top of all of this, after you have made your decision, you need to feign total certainty about it. People being led do not want to think probabilistically.&amp;#8221; This is a key issue that is only going to get worse going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature is hiring a data editor...how will they make sense of the data?</title>
      <link>/2012/04/26/nature-is-hiring-a-data-editor-how-will-they-make/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/04/26/nature-is-hiring-a-data-editor-how-will-they-make/</guid>
      <description>It looks like the journal Nature is hiring a Chief Data Editor (link via Hilary M.). It looks like the primary purpose of this editor is to develop tools for collecting, curating, and distributing data with the goal of improving reproducible research.
The main duties of the editor, as described by the ad are:  Nature Publishing Group is looking for a Chief Editor to develop a product aimed at making research data more available, discoverable and interpretable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Amy Heineike - Director of Mathematics at Quid</title>
      <link>/2012/03/19/interview-with-amy-heineike-director-of-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/19/interview-with-amy-heineike-director-of-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>Amy Heineike  &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m1588osxOV1r08wvg.jpg&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;Amy Heineike is the Director of Mathematics at &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://quid.com/&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Quid&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, a startup that seeks to understand technology development and dissemination through data analysis. She was the first employee at Quid, where she helped develop their technology early on. She has been recognized as one of the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://thephenomlist.com/lists/8/people/32&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;top Big Data Scientists&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;. As a part of our ongoing &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://simplystatistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why statisticians should join and launch startups</title>
      <link>/2012/01/23/why-statisticians-should-join-and-launch-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 14:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/23/why-statisticians-should-join-and-launch-startups/</guid>
      <description>The tough economic times we live in, and the potential for big paydays, have made entrepreneurship cool. From the venture capitalist-in-chief, to the javascript coding mayor of New York, everyone is on board. No surprise there, successful startups lead to job creation which can have a major positive impact on the economy. The game has been dominated for a long time by the folks over in CS. But the value of many recent startups is either based on, or can be magnified by, good data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grad students in (bio)statistics - do a postdoc!</title>
      <link>/2011/12/28/grad-students-in-bio-statistics-do-a-postdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2011 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/28/grad-students-in-bio-statistics-do-a-postdoc/</guid>
      <description>Up until about 20 years ago, postdocs were scarce in Statistics. In contrast, during the same time period, it was rare for a Biology PhD to go straight into a tenure track position.
Driven mostly by the availability of research funding for those working in applied areas, postdocs are becoming much more common in our field and I think this is great. It is great for PhD students to expand their horizons during two years in which they don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about teaching, committee meetings, or grant writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Obama need statisticians?</title>
      <link>/2011/09/29/why-does-obama-need-statisticians/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 16:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/29/why-does-obama-need-statisticians/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;#8217;s worth following up a little on why the Obama campaign is recruiting statisticians (note to Karen: I am not looking for a new job!). Here&amp;#8217;s the blurb for the position of &amp;#8220;Statistical Modeling Analyst&amp;#8221;:
 The Obama for America Analytics Department analyzes the campaign&amp;#8217;s data to guide election strategy and develop quantitative, actionable insights that drive our decision-making. Our team&amp;#8217;s products help direct work on the ground, online and on the air.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>