<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abstract Thinking on Tristan&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/tags/abstract-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abstract Thinking on Tristan&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 16:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/abstract-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>In which Brian debates abstraction with T-Bone</title>
      <link>/2012/08/06/in-which-brian-debates-abstraction-with-t-bone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 16:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/06/in-which-brian-debates-abstraction-with-t-bone/</guid>
      <description>_Editor&amp;#8217;s Note: This is the first in a set of point-counterpoint posts related to the value of abstract thinking in graduate education that we teased a few days ago. Brian Caffo, recently installed Graduate Program Director at the best Biostat department in the country, has kindly agreed to lead off with the case for abstraction. We&amp;#8217;ll follow up later in the week with my counterpoint. In the meantime, there have already been a number of really interesting and insightful comments inspired by our teaser post that are well worth reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How important is abstract thinking for graduate students in statistics?</title>
      <link>/2012/07/27/how-important-is-abstract-thinking-for-graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 13:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/27/how-important-is-abstract-thinking-for-graduate/</guid>
      <description>A recent lunchtime discussion here at Hopkins brought up the somewhat-controversial topic of abstract thinking in our graduate program. We, like a lot of other biostatistics/statistics programs, require our students to take measure theoretic probability as part of the curriculum. The discussion started as a conversation about whether we should require measure theoretic probability for our students. It evolved into a discussion of the value of abstract thinking (and whether measure theoretic probability was a good tool to measure abstract thinking).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>