<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:47:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s wrong with the predicting h-index paper.</title>
      <link>/2012/10/10/whats-wrong-with-the-predicting-h-index-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/10/whats-wrong-with-the-predicting-h-index-paper/</guid>
      <description>_Editor&amp;#8217;s Note: I recently posted about a paper in Nature that purported to predict the H-index. The authors contacted me to get my criticisms, then responded to those criticisms. They have requested the opportunity to respond publicly, and I think it is a totally reasonable request. Until there is a better comment generating mechanism at the journal level, this seems like as good a forum as any to discuss statistical papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is an awesome paper all students in statistics should read</title>
      <link>/2012/10/03/this-is-an-awesome-paper-all-students-in-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 15:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/03/this-is-an-awesome-paper-all-students-in-statistics/</guid>
      <description>The paper is a review of how to do software development for academics. I saw it via C. Titus Brown (who we have interviewed), he is also a co-author. How to write software (particularly for other people) is something that is under emphasized in many curricula. But it turns out this is also one of the more important components of disseminating your work in modern applied statistics. My only wish is that there was an accompanying website with resources/links for people to chase down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A statistician and Apple fanboy buys a Chromebook...and loves it!</title>
      <link>/2012/01/09/a-statistician-and-apple-fanboy-buys-a-chromebook-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/09/a-statistician-and-apple-fanboy-buys-a-chromebook-and/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;#8217;t mean to brag, but I was an early Apple Fanboy - not sure that is something to brag about now that I write it down. I convinced my advisor to go to all Macs in our lab in 2004. Since then I have been pretty dedicated to the brand, dutifully shelling out almost 2g&amp;#8217;s every time I need a new laptop. I love the way Macs just work (until they don&amp;#8217;t and you need a new laptop).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>