<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moocs on Tristan Berchoux</title>
    <link>/tags/moocs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moocs on Tristan Berchoux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 by Tristan Berchoux</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/moocs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of education is plain text</title>
      <link>/2017/06/13/the-future-of-education-is-plain-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/13/the-future-of-education-is-plain-text/</guid>
      <description>I was recently at a National Academy meeting on Envisioning the Data Science Curriculum. It was a fun meeting and one of the questions that came up was what kind of infrastructure do we need to enable shared curricula, compatibility across schools, and not reinventing the wheel. My answer to this question was that we need lecture notes stored in plain text files (like rmarkdown files) and data stored in csv files with direct links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (1/27/2013)</title>
      <link>/2013/01/27/sunday-datastatistics-link-roundup-1272013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 10:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/27/sunday-datastatistics-link-roundup-1272013/</guid>
      <description>Wisconsin is decoupling the education and degree granting components of education. This means if you take a MOOC like mine, Brian&amp;rsquo;s or Roger&amp;rsquo;s and there is an equivalent class to pass at Wisconsin, you can take the exam and get credit. This is big. (via Rafa) 1. Wisconsin is decoupling the education and degree granting components of education. This means if you take a MOOC like mine, Brian&amp;rsquo;s or Roger&amp;rsquo;s and there is an equivalent class to pass at Wisconsin, you can take the exam and get credit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday data/statistics link roundup (1/20/2013)</title>
      <link>/2013/01/20/sunday-datastatistics-link-roundup-1202013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 10:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/20/sunday-datastatistics-link-roundup-1202013/</guid>
      <description>This might be short. I have a couple of classes starting on Monday. The first is our 1. This might be short. I have a couple of classes starting on Monday. The first is our class. This is one of my favorite classes to teach, our Ph.D. students are pretty awesome and they always amaze me with what they can do. The other is my Coursera debut in Data Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Data/Statistics Link Roundup (11/4/12)</title>
      <link>/2012/11/04/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-11-4-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 14:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/04/sunday-data-statistics-link-roundup-11-4-12/</guid>
      <description>Brian Caffo headlines the WaPo article about massive online open courses. He is the driving force behind our department&amp;#8217;s involvement in offering these massive courses. I think this sums it up: `“I can’t use another word than unbelievable,” Caffo said. Then he found some more: “Crazy . . . surreal . . . heartwarming.”&amp;#8217; A really interesting discussion of why &amp;#8220;A Bet is a Tax on B.S.&amp;#8221;. It nicely describes why intelligent betters must be disinterested in the outcome, otherwise they will end up losing money.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>